- 嘿 谁要法国吐司？ - 给我一点
- Hey. Who wants French toast?     - Oh, I'll have some.
我也要 牛奶和鸡蛋在冰箱里 谢谢
Me too. Eggs and milk in the fridge. Thanks.
喔
Ow.
- 怎么回事？甜心    - 我的手怪怪的
- Oh, what's the matter, honey?     - My hand feels weird.
因为我已经订婚的关系吧
I guess it's because I'm engaged.
- 什么时候会开始变得烦人？ - 开始？
- When will that start getting annoying?     - Start?
开始计划婚礼吧
So let's actually get started on the wedding plans.
- 好    - 现在就开始？
- Okay.     - Already?
有很多事要做 要想花…
Yeah, we got a lot to do. We gotta think about the flowers...
外烩 音乐…
...the caterers, the music...
- 我觉得音乐的安排…   - 钱德 太多意见了
- Oh, I got some thoughts on the music...     - Chandler, too many cooks...
给你良心的建议 你只需要出现 说对名字就好了
Take it from me. All you have to do is show up and try to say the right name.
好
Okay.
- 那是什么？ - 老天 是婚礼计划书？
- What in God's name is that?     - Oh, my God, the wedding book?
四年级后我就没看到它了
I haven't seen that since the 4th grade.
这里面什么都有 比如说 地点
This baby has everything. Take, you know, locations for instance:
先以字母顺序排列 再以地理位置排列…
First organized alphabetically, then geographically...
然后以大小排列
...then by square footage.
好聪明
That is so smart. Ha.
快溜 快溜 就趁现在
Break it off. Ahem. Break it off, now.
所以以上证明了…
And that should conclusively prove...
（侏罗纪公园）是我先想到的
...that I had the idea for Jurassic Park first.
- 我们来看看…   - 罗斯
- Now, let's take a look...      - Hey, Ross.
菲比 你来干什么？
Phoebe, oh, my God, what are you doing here?
我有事和你说 很紧急 有关摩妮卡和钱德
I need to talk to you. It's pretty urgent. It's about Monica and Chandler.
我的天 当然
Oh, my God. Um, of course.
等我一下
Uh, would you please excuse me for a moment?
你们知道彼此从哪儿来的吗？ 何不…？
Um, heh, do you know each other's hometowns? Why don't you?
怎么回事？
What's going on?
没什么 我在想 既然他们刚订婚…
Well, um, not much. I was just thinking that since those guys just got engaged...
应该多给他们一些独处的时间
...that maybe it'd be nice if they had some privacy.
所以我可以搬去你家几天吗？
So could I just move in with you for a couple days?
额…
Um...
好 当然 摩妮卡和钱德 发生了什么事吗？
Okay, yeah, sure. But what's wrong with Monica and Chandler?
没事 怎么了？
Nothing. Why?
菲比 是你说很紧急的
Phoebe, you said it was urgent.
是啊 我的电影5分钟后 要开演了
Oh, yeah, it is. I'm going to the movies and it starts in like five minutes.
你知道我有一屋子的学生在这儿吗？
Do you realize I have a classroom full of students?
抱歉 我很没礼貌 有人想要一起去看电影吗？
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm so rude. Does anyone want to come to the movies?
我还没和我爸妈谈到预算…
I haven't cleared the budget with my parents yet...
不过跟我说说音乐部分的安排
...but tell me how this is for music.
进时用弦乐四重奏 鸡尾酒会时安排爵士三重奏…
All right, um, a string quartet for the processional, a jazz trio for cocktails...
跳舞时用湾市摇滚…
...the Bay City Rollers for dancing...
等一下 那是我的六年级婚礼
Wait, that was for my 6th grade wedding.
也不可能用他们 伊恩不演出了 还有德苗克…
Well, you couldn't get them anyway. Ian doesn't play anymore, and Derek...
我不该知道德苗克这个人的
Well, Derek is a name I shouldn't know.
摩妮卡 有没有别的枕头 比较舒服一点的？
Hey, Mon, do you have another pillow, you know, something a little snugglier?
你为什么不回去你家 却要在这里睡？
Why are you napping over here instead of over at your place?
- 因为鸭子   - 什么 鸭子？
- The duck.     - What, the duck?
怎么 现在鸭子又做了什么？
What the hell did the damn duck do now?
它不是在那里生病的…
Uh, well, he did not get sick somewhere in there...
而且立刻被发现 并妥当处理干净了
...and it was immediately found and properly cleaned up.
我可以看这本书吗…
Now, do I get to look at this book...
还是只有和婚礼相关人员可以看？
...or is it just for people who are actually involved in the wedding?
你当然可以看 我要你的意见
Of course you can look at it. Yeah, I want your opinion too.
- 来   - 该你了
- Okay. - Here you go.
- 桌子中间的花饰？ - 桌子中间的花饰
- What do you think about centerpieces?     - Centerpieces.
- 玫瑰还是百合？ - 当然是玫瑰
- Roses or lilies?     - Definitely roses.
我觉得它们比较像婚礼用花
Well, I just think they're a bit more wedding-y, you know.
- 但很清楚应该选百合   - 老天 简直就是心有灵犀
- But lilies are the clear choice.     - Oh, my God, it's like one mind.
额
Uh-huh.
各位 各位 让我休息好不好
Guys, guys, you gotta let me nap.
不然我会脾气不好
I'm gonna get cranky.
乔伊 走廊对面有很好的沙发
Joey, there is a perfectly good couch across the hall.
是很不错…
Yes, it is perfectly good...
但那不是鸭子生病的地方之一
...and it is not one of the places the duck got sick.
什么？
What?
- 好 我要走了   - 乔伊 鸭子到底做了什么？
- All right, I'm gonna go.     - Joey, what did the duck do?
我不知道 但他没吃你的面霜
I don't know, but he did not eat your face cream.
小朋友
Hey, little buddy.
你觉得如何？
How you feeling? Aah.
那面霜里到底有什么？
What the hell is in that face cream?
好软
That's so soft.
有枕头套耶
Pillowcases.
噢
Oh, ah.
"柔达看着扫烟囱的人 她的父亲是个传道者…"
"Zelda looked at the chimney sweep. Her father, the vicar..."
传道者？
Vicar?
"还有好几小时才会回来
"...wouldn't be home for hours.
她欲火中烧
Her loins were burning.
她不顾一切伸出手去抓住他的…"
She threw caution to the wind and reached out and grabbed his..."
哇哦
Whoa.
这是色情小说
This is a dirty book.
菲比？
Uh, Phoebe?
嗨 罗斯
Oh, Ross, hi.
- 菲比 你在干什么？ - 抱歉 我有客人在
- Phoebe, what are you doing?     - I'm sorry, I'm with a client right now.
- 菲比   - 好吧 我们到外面谈
- Phoebe.     - Okay, let's talk outside.
菲比 你不可以在我家帮人家按摩
Phoebe, you can't massage people in my apartment.
有什么大不了的 我在摩妮卡和钱德家都可以
What's the big deal? I did it at Monica and Chandler's.
他们知道吗？
And they knew about it?
好吧 罗斯 到底怎么回事？
Okay, look, Ross, what is this really about?
这是我家 我希望能自由出入
Look, this is my home, and I want to be able to come and go whenever I want.
好 我会找其他地方 来做我其他的客人
Okay. I will find someplace else to do the rest of my appointments.
我只是觉得 这有什么大不了的？
I just don't know what the big deal is.
大不了的地方就是我不要光着身子 身上油油的陌生人在我家…
The big deal is I don't want naked, greasy strangers in my apartment...
当我想回家放松 拿一片拼图…啤酒 冰啤酒时
...when I want to kick back with a puzzle... Beer, cold beer.
嘿 乔伊 你好吗？
Hey, Joey. What are you doing?
扫地 怎么？ 挑起你的性趣吗？
Sweeping. Why? Does it turn you on?
不会
No.
额
Hmm.
如果我扫的是烟囱呢？
What if I was, uh, sweeping a chimney?
乔伊 你吃了我的面霜吗？
Joey, did you eat my face cream?
你去哪儿？ 传道者要几小时后才会回来
Where are you going? The vicar won't be home for hours.
乔伊
Joey...
你从那儿学到那个词的？
...where did you learn that word?
你想是哪里…
Where do you think...
柔达？
...Zelda?
- 你看了我的书？ - 对
- You found my book?     - Yeah, I did.
乔伊 你到我房里干什么？
Joey, what are you doing going into my bedroom?
抱歉 我只是小睡一下
Okay, I'm sorry. I went in there to take a nap.
我知道 我不应该 可是你有色情小说
And I know I shouldn't have, but you got porn.
额
Ugh.
知道吗？ 我不在乎 我不为我的书感到丢脸
You know what? I don't care. I'm not ashamed of my book.
女人享受一点情色没什么不对
There's nothing wrong with a woman enjoying a little erotica.
是女性性感的健康表达…
It's just a healthy expression of female sexuality...
那是你永远都不会了解的
...which, by the way, is something that you will never understand.
你有色情小说
You got porn.
- 你好   - 嗨 菲比在吗？
- Hello.     - Hi, is, uh, Phoebe here?
- 不 今晚她不在   - 真是的
- Uh, no, no, she's out for the night.     - Oh, great.
可以帮你什么忙吗？
Heh. Can I help you with something?
我不知道 你是按摩师吗？
I don't know. Are you a masseur?
是 我是
Yes, I am.
太好了 爸？
Great. Dad?
谢谢你 一小时后我来接他
Thank you so much. I'll be back to pick him up in an hour.
钱德 你父母听到你…
So, Chandler, your parents must've been thrilled...
订婚一定很开心
...when you told them you were engaged.
哦 是啊 我应该打电话给他们
Oh, yeah. I should probably call them.
我记得我们刚订婚的时候
I remember when we first got engaged.
- 我没听过这个故事   - 爸 你不必…
- I don't think I've heard that story.     - Dad, you don't...
我让茱蒂怀孕了
Well, I'd gotten Judy pregnant.
我还是不知道怎么发生的
I still don't know how.
你不知道怎么发生的？ 你的狗 以为我的避孕器是磨牙玩具
You don't know how? Your dog thought my diaphragm was a chew toy.
真感人的故事
What a sweet story.
至少你不是在五年级的 万圣节派对听到这故事
At least you're not hearing it at your 5th grade Halloween party.
是他们要听吓人的故事
What? They wanted a scary story.
我们对婚礼计划很兴奋
Anyway, we're really excited about our wedding plans.
很快我们就要从婚礼基金 提一大笔钱
Pretty soon we'll be making a big withdrawal from the Monica wedding fund.
- 什么？ - 杰克 你告诉她 我做不到
- What?     - You tell her, Jack. I can't do it.
我的婚礼基金还在 对吧？
What happened? You still have the wedding fund, don't you?
我们有 只是现在叫做 "海滩别墅"
We have it. Only now we call it "the beach house."
我不敢相信 你把我的婚礼基金 花在海滩别墅？
I can't believe you spent my wedding fund on the beach house.
对不起 我们以为…
We're sorry. We assumed...
等你30岁后 你会自己付钱
...if you got married after you turned 30 you'd pay for it yourself.
你们买海滩别墅时我才23岁
You bought the beach house when I was 23.
那也表示 你在海边享受了7年好时光…
Which means you had seven years of beach fun...
那可是无价的
...and you can't put a price on that, sweetie.
我们觉得很抱歉
We really do feel bad about this though.
你和理查交往时 我们又开始存钱
We started saving again when you dated Richard.
结果你们闹翻了 我们重新装潢了厨房
But then that went to hell, so we redid the kitchen.
那当我开始和钱德约会呢？
What about when I started dating Chandler?
我们以为钱德不会求婚
It was Chandler. We didn't think he'd ever propose.
很显然开始吃饭时 我酒喝得不够
Clearly I did not start drinking enough at the start of the meal. Heh.
我不相信竟然没有钱让我结婚
I can't believe there is no money for my wedding.
也许还有 如果你爸没有…
We might still have some if your father hadn't thought...
在网上卖冰的话
...to sell ice over the Internet.
- 那个主意看来很简单   - 只能用"笨"来形容
- It seemed like such a simple idea.     - Stupid, Jack. The word is stupid.
我不想再细听了
All right, enough. I don't want to hear about it anymore.
祝你好运 钱德
Good luck, Chandler.
现在我要…
Okay, now I'm going to...
摸你了
...touch you.
好软
Oh, that's soft.
我不敢相信 你认为你的父母可能帮忙付吗？
I can't believe this. Do you think your parents could help pay for it?
我不知道
I don't know.
我妈大部分的钱 都花在她第四次的婚礼了
My mother spent most of her money on her fourth wedding.
剩下的钱她离婚要用
She's saving the rest for her divorce.
而我爸存的钱用在…
And any extra cash my father has, he saves for his yearly trips to...
到桃利屋的年度旅行
...Dollywood.
你们的晚餐发生什么事了？
What happened at dinner?
我父母把婚礼基金花掉了
My parents spent the money for our wedding.
我的天 你点了什么菜？
My God, what did you order?
等一下 没有婚礼基金了？ 太惨了
Wait, there's no money? Well, this is terrible.
你们必须在活动中心结婚了
You guys are gonna have to get married in, like, a rec center.
- 亲爱的 没关系的   - 不 有关系
- Honey, it's gonna be okay.     - No, it's not gonna be okay. It sucks.
- 没有乐团 没有百合   - 那很好啊
- No swing band, no lilies.     - No, you know what? It's gonna be okay.
你不需要有这种…
I mean, you don't need to have this...
意大利野宴
...rustic Italian feast, you know?
你不需要这种订做的帝国式腰线 公主型丝缎礼服
And you don't need this custom-made empire-waisted, duchess satin gown.
你可以买现成的礼服
You can wear off-the-rack.
真的不会有问题的
Look, it really is gonna be okay.
重要的是我们彼此相爱 要结婚了
The important thing is that we love each other and we're gonna get married.
你知不知道"现成的"是什么意思？
Do you even understand what "off-the-rack" means?
你为什么不自己付钱呢？
Why don't you just pay for it yourself?
怎么付？ 我没钱
How? I don't have any money.
- 我有   - 多少？
- Well, I have some.     - How much?
将近有…
Well, close to...
- 哇 你开玩笑？ - 多少？
- Whoa! Are you kidding me?     - What? How much?
- 够办婚礼计划A   - 真的？
- It's enough for wedding scenario A.     - Really?
你真好 努力存钱的人
How great are you, you little saver? Heh.
正是理想婚礼的预算
The amount you have is exactly the budget of my dream wedding.
喔 你们真是天造地设的一对
Oh, you guys are so made for each other.
你不是要把所有的钱 都花在婚礼上吧？
Well, you're not suggesting we spend all of the money on the wedding?
是啊
Uh, yeah.
我花了六年存到这些…
Look, Mon, I've been saving this money for six years...
有些是将来要用的 不是都花在一场派对上的
...and I kind of have some of it earmarked for the future, not just for a party.
哇 钱德先生 你好啊
Wow. Hello, Mr. Chandler.
甜心 这是我们一生中 最重要的一天
Sweetie, this is the most special day of our lives.
我知道 宝贝 但我不要把钱都花在一场派对上
I realize that, honey, but I'm not gonna spend all the money on one party.
甜心 我爱你
Honey, um, I love you. Heh.
但如果你再叫我们的婚礼 一场派对…
But, um, if you call our wedding a party one more time...
你可能不会被邀请
...you may not get invited.
钱可以再赚 但我们只结婚一次
We can always earn more money, okay? But we're only gonna get married once.
我了解 但我非常坚决 我的答案是不
Look, I understand, but I have to put my foot down, okay? The answer is no.
你很坚决？
You're gonna have to put your foot down?
对 我是
Yes, I am.
有钱和有一只坚定的手
Wow. Money and a firm hand.
祝你好运 钱德
Good luck, Chandler.
(中央咖啡厅)
- 嘿 瑞秋   - 乔伊
- Hey, Rach.     - Joey.
瑞秋 有没有闻到烟味？
Hey, Rach, do you smell smoke?
我懂了 烟 烟囱 扫烟囱的人 很好笑
Uh-huh. I get it. Smoke, chimney, chimney sweep. Very funny. Ha, ha.
不 不 我说真的 你没闻到？
No, no, no, I'm serious. You don't smell it?
有东西着火了
Something's on fire.
我没闻到什么
No, I don't smell anything.
你知道吗？ 可能是你熊熊的欲火
Oh, you know what? It's probably just your burning loins.
- 你们在讲什么？ - 没什么
- Hey, what are you guys talking about?     - Nothing.
讨厌 咖啡冷了
Mm, damn, this coffee's cold.
瑞秋 可以在你身上加温一下吗？
Hey, Rach, do you mind if I heat this up on your loins?
乔伊 你竟然告诉他…
You know, I cannot believe you told him. Joey...
我猜你是在我们分手后买了那本书
So I guess you bought that book after we broke up, huh?
是啊 因为第一本 在我们交往时被翻烂了
Uh-huh, I did, because I wore out my first copy when I was with you.
是吗？
Oh, yeah? Yeah?
我们交往时 我看了一大堆色情杂志
Well, uh, when we were going out, I read tons of porno magazines.
怎么样？
'Sup?
罗斯 你怎么可以 那样对待一位老先生？
Ross, how could you do that to an old man?
失陪了 小姐们
Excuse me, ladies.
什么啊？
I'm sorry?
我的按摩客人 亚瑟
My massage client, Arthur.
他女儿说替我工作的那个人…
His daughter called and said some guy that worked for me...
今天下午替他做了很奇怪的按摩
...gave him a really weird massage this afternoon.
我做了很专业的按摩
I gave him an extremely professional massage.
他说你用木汤匙戳他
He said you poked at him with wooden spoons.
好吧 不是传统的按摩
Okay, so it wasn't a traditional massage.
可是我有用筷子替他刺激穴道…
But I did give him acupressure with a pair of chopsticks...
并温和地用拖把去角质
...and I gently exfoliated him with a mop.
他再也不会来了 你害我一星期少进帐八十元
Well, he's never coming back, okay? You just cost me $80 a week.
这是你的错 你没更改他约的时间
You know what? This is your fault. You didn't move his appointment.
我的错？ 你不必替他按摩的
Oh, it's my fault? You didn't have to massage him.
你可以请他回去的
You could've sent him away.
你不必用玩具推土机 在他背上滚来滚去
You could've not rolled Tonka trucks up and down his back.
他说他很喜欢
He said he liked that.
你对 你对 对不起
You're right, you're right. I'm sorry.
老兄 你干嘛按摩一位老先生？
Dude, what are you massaging an old man for?
- 他女儿很辣   - 懂了
- His daughter was hot.     - Gotcha.
- 嘿   - 嘿
- Hey.     - Hey.
听着…
Listen, um...
我想过了
...I've been thinking.
要你把所有的钱 花在婚礼上很不公平
And it's not fair for me to ask you to spend all your money on our wedding.
你很辛苦才赚来的
I mean, you work really hard for that.
- 嗯   - 是你赚来的
- Well.     - Well, you work for that.
我也想过了
Look, I thought about it too.
对不起 我们应该把 所有的钱花在婚礼的
And I'm sorry. I think we should spend all of the money on the wedding.
- 真的？ - 对 我很坚决
- You do?     - Yeah, I'm putting my foot down.
当我求婚时 我告诉你…
Yeah, look, when I proposed, I told you...
我会尽力让你快乐
...that I would do anything to make you happy.
如果办一场完美婚礼 能让你开心…
And if having the perfect wedding makes you happy...
那我们就这么做
...then that's what we're gonna do.
你对我真好
You are so sweet.
但是 等等
Oh, but wait.
那未来怎么办呢？
What about our...? What about the future and stuff?
管他呢
Ah, forget about the future and stuff.
我们只生两个就好
So we only have two kids.
选一个我们最喜欢的 让他去念大学
You know, we'll pick our favorite and that one will get to go to college.
- 你想过这些？ - 对
- Have you thought about that?     - Yeah.
你本来要几个孩子？
How many kids were we gonna have?
四个 一个男孩 一对双胞胎女儿 再一个男孩
Uh, four. A boy, twin girls and another boy.
你还想过什么？
What else did you think about?
还有我们要住的地方
Well, heh, stuff like where we'd live, you know.
像是在市中心外的小房子…
Like a small place outside the city...
我们的小孩可以学骑单车
...where our kids could learn to ride their bikes and stuff.
可以养只猫咪 脖子上挂着铃铛…
We could have a cat that had a bell on its collar...
每次它跑出小门时 都听得见铃声
...and we could hear it every time it ran through the little kitty door.
在车库上盖个房间 让乔伊终老
Of course we'd have an apartment over the garage where Joey could grow old.
你知道吗？
You know what?
我不要一个盛大的婚礼
I don't want a big, fancy wedding.
- 你要的   - 不
- Sure you do.     - No.
我要你刚刚说的每一样东西 我要一个婚姻
I want everything that you've just said. I want a marriage.
- 你确定？ - 嗯
- You sure?     - Mm-hm.
- 我好爱你   - 我爱你
- I love you so much.     - I love you.
你刚说到将来的时候 你说猫咪
Hey, listen, when you were talking about our future, you said cat.
你指的是狗 对不对？
But you meant dog, right? Ha, ha.
- 对   - 好
- Ha, yeah, totally.     - Oh, good.
你好 柔达
Hello, Zelda.
- 你又是谁呢？ - 传道者
- Who are you supposed to be?     - The vicar.
- 你知道传道者是什么吗？ - 像是个守门员 对不对？
- Do you even know what a vicar is?     - Like a goalie, right?
对
Yeah.
乔伊 我是说真的 够了
Look, Joey, it's enough, all right?
你老是开这些笨玩笑 还有无聊的暗讽…
You keep making these stupid jokes and these sleazy innuendoes...
真的是不好笑
...and it's just not funny anymore.
对不起 瑞秋 对不起
All right, I'm sorry. Rach, I'm sorry. Okay? I'm sorry.
也许我可以在谷仓里 粗暴地对待你来补偿你
Maybe I could make it up to you by taking you roughly in the barn.
额
Ugh.
好了 够了 你想做吗？ 我们做吧
All right, you know what? That's it. You want to do it? Let's do it.
哈？
Huh?
没错 我想和你做
That's right. I want to do it with you.
我一直想抗拒 但你说的每一句话 都深深打动了我
Been trying to fight it, but you just said all the right things.
我有吗？
Uh, I did?
有 我想得到你的身体想了好久
Yeah, oh, I've been waiting so long to get on that body.
- 我的身体？ - 对 没错
- This body?     - Yeah, that's right.
乔伊 放马过来吧
Come on, Joey, sex me up.
你听起来开始像 第七章里的屠夫妻子
Hey, you're starting to sound like the butcher's wife there in chapter seven.
来吧 不要让我等 脱掉你的衣服
Oh, come on, now. Don't keep me waiting. Get those clothes off.
但留着你的头盔 因为 这会是一场狂风暴雨
But I would keep that helmet on, because you're in for a rough ride.
我不要 我好害怕
I don't want to. I'm scared.